When America marched off to war the women marched into the
factory. From then on...nothing was the same.
Swing Shift is a drama, romance, war film directed by Jonathan Demme.
In 1941 America, Kay and her husband are happy enough
until he enlists after Pearl Harbor.
Against his wishes, she takes a job at the local aircraft plant
where she meets Hazel, the singer from across the way.
The two soon become firm friends and with the other
girls become increasingly expert workers.
As the war drags on, Kay finally dates her trumpet-playing
foreman and life gets more complicated.
Kay Walsh, played by Goldie Hawn.
Lucky Lockhart, played by Kurt Russell.
Hazel Zanussi, played by Christine Lahti.
Biscuits Toohey, played by Fred Ward.
Jack Walsh, played by Ed Harris.
Annie, played by Sudie Bond.
Swing Shift is a 1984 American romantic drama directed by Jonathan Demme,
and produced by and starring Goldie Hawn, with Kurt Russell.
It also features Christine Lahti, Fred Ward, Ed Harris and
Holly Hunter, in one of her earlier movie roles.
The film was a box office bomb, grossing just $6.6
million against its $15 million budget.
Lahti earned a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress.
The film explores themes of world war ii, home
front, riveter, arms industry, 1940s.
The tone is emotional.